bupa.com.au 2011-09-23

# Privacy & Security - Bupa Australia

## Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. That's why we want you to know about our information handling practices.

We collect personal information (including information about your health) in various ways to enable us to provide you with health insurance and related services.

For example, we collect personal information when you complete an application form at a retail centre or online, or when you provide details over the phone. When you make a claim for benefits, we collect information from you and/or your provider about your hospital or extras services or treatment to enable us to process your claim. Where we collect information from you or your provider, we only collect the information we need to fulfill the relevant purpose. We may also collect information about you through our agents.

There are a number of laws which require us to collect information about you, including the Private Health Insurance Reforms Act 2007.

If we don't receive the necessary information, we will not be able to pay you benefits, or provide you with health insurance or related services. You have the right at any time to access information we hold about you.

Bupa Australia does not sell your personal information to anyone.

In providing you with our products and services, we may disclose personal information to other organisations or agencies that are bound to handle your information in the same way we do. The circumstances where we may disclose your personal information include:

  * When another organisation helps us process transactions, store data, access data or provide services to you in order for them to perform their role. Our business terms prohibit our contractors from using your personal information for anything other than related to Bupa Australia's business.
  * Where laws require or allow us to provide information to a government agency or organisation (e.g. the Department of Health and Ageing and Medicare Australia).
  * When a hospital or provider helps administer a claim that has been made for hospital or ancillary items or services (e.g. hospitals, doctors and other ancillary providers).
  * When membership details and benefits paid need to be confirmed to the policyholder.

Some of the organisations and agencies that we may disclose your personal information to are located outside Victoria in other States or Territories in Australia. Bupa Australia may send your personal information to them in the course of providing you with our products and services (including by transmitting it electronically).

When we do so, they are required to handle your personal information in generally the same way we do. We do everything reasonable to ensure your personal information is kept secure from unauthorised access or disclosure.

Other companies in the Bupa Australia Group of companies may write to you about products, services or benefits offered by them. You have the right to ask these organisations for access to information they hold about you. Your personal information will only be disclosed to them for the purpose of writing to you about their products and/or services. If you do not wish to us to disclose your information in this manner, please contact Bupa Australia on 131 243.

From time to time, Bupa Australia may write to you about products, services or benefits from affiliate organisations which Bupa Australia considers of potential benefit to you and your family. If you do not wish us to communicate this information to you, please contact Bupa Australia on 131 243.

## Security

This site uses SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption to keep your transactions secure and private. SSL is the industry standard for data encryption. It provides a secure link between your browser and our server, and scrambles your personal information to ensure it is kept private during transmission over the Internet.

### Information Handling Policy

For more detail about how we use personal information you can view our Information Handling Policy.

### Accessing your details

At any time, you can ask us for access to information we hold about you by:

  * Completing a request form at a retail centre
  * Calling Bupa Australia enquiries on 131 243
